Guide to the Ulysses Kay papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Music by Kay, 1939-1991
  - Two Songs for Children, 1966
    - Score, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Scores with correspondence, 1966-1968 (2 items) (Box 23, Folder 6)
      (correspondence from Juilliard administrative assistant George Dickey)
    - Juilliard Repertory Library, Vocal Volume 3 and advertisement, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      (Two Songs on pages 34-37)
  - Markings, 1965-1966
    - Text, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Preliminary sketches, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Sketches, 1965-1966 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Full score, undated (Box 61)
    - Miniature score, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Miniature scores, 1968 (2 items) (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Traveler Wanted, 1966
    - Copy with outline of commercial, circa 1966 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Sketch, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Sketch, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Sketch, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Holographs of parts, 1966 (5 items) (Box 23, Folder 10)
      (incomplete set; contain additional markings)
  - The Birds, 1966
    - Preliminary sketches, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Full sketch, 1965-1966 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Full score, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Choir scores, 1969 (10 items) (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Aulos, 1966-1967
    - Preliminary sketches, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Full sketch, 1966-1967 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Set of parts, undated (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1967 (3 items) (Box 2, Folder 34)
      (from John Solum; contains markings)
    - Note, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Piano reduction with separate flute part, 1980 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Stephen Crane Set, 1967
    - First typescript of text, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
      (includes note; contains markings)
    - Working typescript of text, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - 12-tone matrix, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - First sketch, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Full sketch, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Set of instrumental parts, undated (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Transparent choral score, undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Choir scores, 1972 (2 items) (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Symphony, 1967
    - 12-tone matrix, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Preliminary sketches, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Full sketch, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Notes, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Full score, circa 1967 (Box 62)
  - Bleeker [sic] Street Suite, 1967-1968
    - Sketch, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Holograph, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Heralds I, 1968
    (originally Heralds)
    - Sketches, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Sketch, circa 1968 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Full score, undated (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Full score, undated (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Full score, undated (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Full score, undated (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Full score, undated (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Theater Set, 1968
    - Sketches, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Correction notes, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Note on reverse of correspondence, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 44)
      (correspondence from R. Ora Williams regarding publication of article in The Camp Fire Girl)
    - Full score, circa 1968 (Box 63)
    - Full score, circa 1968 (Box 64)
    - Miniature scores with note, 1971 (2 items) (Box 2, Folder 45)
      (note originally inserted inside score)
  - Scherzi Musicali, 1968
    - Early sketch, 1950 (Box 24, Folder 11)
      (also includes sketch for "Serenade (pianoforte 4 hands")
    - 12-tone matrix, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 12)
      (includes examples of types of chords on inside)
    - Preliminary sketches, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Notes, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Full sketch, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 13)
      (includes holographs of parts for Three Fanfares for Four Trumpets (1942), on the versos of pages 1-4)
    - Full score, circa 1968 (Box 65)
    - Miniature score, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      (marking on front cover)
    - Miniature score, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Once There Was a Man: A Covenant for our time, 1969
    - Drafts of text, circa 1969 (4 items) (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Text with Kay's composition notes, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Full sketch, part 1, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Full sketch, part 2, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      (page 29A on inside of pages 27-28)
    - Sketch of piano reduction, part 1, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      (contains narrator part)
    - Sketch of piano reduction, part 2, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 3)
      (contains chorus part)
    - Notes, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 25)
      (includes information about librettist and chorus text with markings)
    - Proof for piano reduction, part 1, undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
      (with narrator part; contains markings)
    - Proof for piano reduction, part 2, undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
      (with chorus part; contains markings)
    - Score of piano reduction with list of corrections, undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
      (contains markings; list of corrections found inside front cover)
    - Score of piano reduction, undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Full score, undated (Box 66)
  - Parables, 1969-1970
    - Text, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - First sketch, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Full sketch, 1969-1970 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Full score, 1970 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Choir scores, 1970 (2 items) (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - The Capitoline Venus, 1969-1970
    - Original libretto, circa 1969 (Box 2, Folder 56)
      (contains markings by librettist Judith Dvorkin)
    - Copy of original libretto, circa 1969 (Box 2, Folder 57)
      (contains additional markings by Kay)
    - Revised libretto, circa 1969 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Outline of cast/instrumentation and layout of scene, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - First sketch, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Full sketch, 1969-1970 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      (overture at end)
    - Notes, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Sketch of piano reduction, circa 1970, (2 Folders) (Box 26, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Proofs for score of piano reduction, undated (2 items) (Box 27, Folder 1)
      (second copy incomplete; contain markings)
    - Score of piano reduction, undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Score of piano reduction, undated (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Full score, undated (Box 67)
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 61)
      (from librettist Judith Dvorkin regarding corrections)
    - List of corrections for full score, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Facets, 1970-1971
    - 12-tone matrix, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Full score, undated (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Triple Set, 1970-1971 (originally College Set)
    - Texts, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Preliminary sketches, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Sketch of "Ode: To the Cuckoo", 1970 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Sketch of "A Toast", 1970 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Full sketch, 1970-1971 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Copy of full sketch, circa 1971 (Box 25, Folder 13)
      (copy made before markings)
    - Copy of full sketches for "Ode: To the Cuckoo" and "Had I a Heart", circa 1971 (Box 39, Folder 4)
      (contains markings and sketches for piano reduction)
    - Choir scores, 1972 (6 items) (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Pentagraph, 1970-1972
    - Texts, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Preliminary sketches, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Sketches, 1970-1972 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Full sketch, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Copy of full sketch, undated (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Note regarding "The Monkey's Glue" with publication information, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Choir scores, 1978 (10 items) (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Four Silhouettes, 1972
    - Sketch, circa 1972 (Box 39, Folder 18)
    - Full score with set of parts, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Five Portraits, 1971-1972
    - First sketch and page of notes, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - 12-tone matrix, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Full sketch, 1971-1972 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Copy of holograph of full score, circa 1972 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Holograph of violin part, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Proof for full score, undated (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Proof for violin part, undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - First Nocturne, 1973
    (see also Second Nocturne, 1973)
    - Preliminary sketches, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 70)
      (also includes sketches for Second Nocturne (1973) and "Nocturne #3")
    - 12-tone matrix, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Full sketch, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 8)
      (includes Second Nocturne, 1973)
    - Holograph, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Copies of holograph, 1973 (2 items) (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Second Nocturne, 1973
    (became second of Two Impromptus, 1986, see also First Nocturne, 1973)
    - Preliminary sketches, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 70)
      (also includes sketches for First Nocturne (1973) and "Nocturne #3")
    - Full sketch, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 8)
      (includes First Nocturne, 1973)
    - Holograph, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Score, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Score, 1973-1986 (Box 28, Folder 13)
      (facsimile; title changed to "Impromptu #2"; contains markings)
  - Harlem Children's Suite, 1973
    - First sketch, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - Notes, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Holograph of full score, circa 1973 (Box 68)
    - Holograph of piano reduction, circa 1973 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - Set of parts, undated (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - Full score, circa 1973 (Box 69)
  - Guitarra, 1973
    - First sketch, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Full sketch, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - Holograph, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 23)
      (includes three draft pages)
    - Score, circa 1973 (Box 28, Folder 24)
    - Score, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 25)
    - Score, 1985 (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - Visions, 1974
    (for William Grant Still on his 80th birthday)
    - Sketch and holograph, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Heralds II, 1974
    - Sketch, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Full score, undated (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Quintet Concerto, 1974
    - First sketch, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Full sketch, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Notes, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Piano reduction, undated (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Full score, undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Two Folksong Settings, 1975
    - Source melodies and texts, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Preliminary sketches, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Full sketch, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - The Bicentennial Musical Celebration: Music for Chorus, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 78)
      (contains markings; Kay's songs on pages 85-93 and pages 102-120)
    - The Bicentennial Musical Celebration: Music for Chorus, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 79)
      (Kay's songs on pages 85-93 and pages 102-120)
  - Epigrams and Hymn, 1975
    - Text, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - First sketch, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Full sketch, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Holograph, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Program note, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Correspondence with list of corrections on reverse, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 83)
      (correspondence from Carl Fischer editor J. Theodore Prochazka)
    - Choir score, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Choir scores, 1975 (2 items) (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - The Western Paradise, 1975
    - First version of text with correspondence, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      (text contains markings; correspondence from librettist Donald Dorr)
    - Copy of first version of text, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Second version of text, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Final version of text, 1975 (2 items) (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - First sketch, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Full sketch, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Sketch of piano reduction, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Other sketches, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Notes, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Piano reduction, circa 1975 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Full score, circa 1975 (Box 29, Folder 12)
      (facsimile; contains markings; note inserted inside front cover)
  - Southern Harmony, 1975
    - Source melodies, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - First sketch, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Full sketch, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Notes, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Outline and program note, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Study scores, 1979 (2 items) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Jubilee, 1974-1976
    - Early version of libretto, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Draft libretto, circa 1975 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      (contains markings; includes correspondence from librettist Donald Dorr)
    - List of libretto corrections and libretto excerpt, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Musical number list, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Potential source melodies, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - First sketch of Act I, Scene 1, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      (followed by supplementary sketches)
    - First sketch of Act I, Scene 2, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - First sketch of Act I, Scene 3, 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      (also function as "full sketch")
    - First sketch of Act II, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - First sketch of Act III, beginning, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      (second part incorporated into full sketch)
    - Full sketch of Act I, Scene 1, 1974-1975 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Full sketch of Act I, Scene 2, 1975 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Full sketch of Act II, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Full sketch of Act III, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 4)
      (includes second part of first sketch)
    - Notes on "centers" (key areas), 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Notes, 1974-1977 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Sketch of piano reduction for Act I, Scene 1, undated (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Sketch of piano reduction for Act I, Scene 2, undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
      (includes list of corrections)
    - Sketch of piano reduction for Act I, Scene 3, undated (Box 31, Folder 2)
      (includes drafts of pages 152 and 153)
    - Sketch of piano reduction for Act II, circa 1976 (Box 31, Folder 3)
      (includes holographs for two excerpts)
    - Sketch of piano reduction for Act III, undated (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Copy of proofs for Act I piano reduction, circa 1976 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Copy of proofs for Act II piano reduction, 1976, (2 Folders) (Box 32, Folder 2 to 3)
      (the contents of Folder 3 precede those of Folder 2; contain markings)
    - Copy of proofs for Act III piano reduction, circa 1976 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Piano reduction for Act I, circa 1976 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Piano reduction for Act I, circa 1976 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Piano reduction for Act II, circa 1976 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Piano reduction for Act III, circa 1976 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Copy of full score for Act II, circa 1976 (Box 70)
    - Copy of full score for Act III, circa 1976 (Box 71)
    - Draft program note, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Statement of concept, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
      (written after second production in 1977)
    - List of possible excerpts and libretto for concert version, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Souvenir Librettos
      - Opera/South, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 23a)
        Contains handwritten comments; most have been crossed out.
      - Souvenir libretto for performance of concert version at Lehman College, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Prologue and Parade, 1977
    (from Concert Sketches, 1965)
    - Full sketch, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Holograph of full score, 1977 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Set of parts, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Set of parts, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 85)
      (missing parts for 2nd alto saxophone)
    - Full score, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - The Waves, 1978
    (words and music by Hillary Kay; transcribed by Ulysses Kay)
    - Full sketch, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Jersey Hours, 1978-1979
    (in three versions: version "A" for voice and solo harp; version "B" for voice and solo piano; version "C" for voice and three harps)
    - First sketch, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Full sketch of version A with occasional sketches for version C, 1978 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Full sketch of version B, circa 1978 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Full sketch of version C, 1979 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Holographs of harp parts for version C, circa 1979 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Notes, circa 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Notes for lecture "Work in Progress", 1979 (Box 4, Folder 34)
      (lecture about Kay's compositional process for Jersey Hours)
    - Title pages from holograph of full score, circa 1979 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Full score for version A, 1979 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Full score for version A, circa 1979 (Box 34, Folder 6)
      (facsimile; redesignated as version B; contains markings and sketches)
    - Copy of proofs for full score of version A, circa 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Copy of proofs for full score of version B, circa 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Copies of proofs for version C harp parts, circa 1979-1981, (3 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 37 to 39)
      (contain markings; part for harp 1 incomplete)
    - Full score for version A, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Full scores for version A, 1981 (2 items) (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Full score for version B, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Full scores for version B, 1981 (2 items) (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Full score for version C, circa 1979 (Box 72)
  - Chariots, 1979
    - Text, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Preliminary sketches, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Partial sketch, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Full sketch, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Partial sketch with full orchestration, 1979 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Notes, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Full score, 1979 (Box 73)
    - Study scores, 1983 (2 items) (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Cadenza for Mozart's Piano Concerto
    - Full sketch, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 30)
      (for Jeana Neal at Brevard)
  - Tromba, 1983
    - Early sketches and notes, 1972-1973 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Sketches and notes, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Full sketch, 1983 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Draft pages from holographs, 1983 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Full score, circa 1983 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Trumpet part, circa 1983 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Full score with separate trumpet part, 1985 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Festival Psalms, 1983
    - First sketch, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Full sketch, 1983 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Notes, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Holograph and copy, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Full score, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Copy of full score, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Five Winds, 1984
    (originally Divertimento)
    - Sketches and notes, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Full sketch, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Copy of holograph, circa 1984 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Full scores, circa 1984 (2 items) (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Frederick Douglass, 1977-1985
    - Plot summaries, undated (2 items) (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Excerpt from libretto for finale of Act I, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Early version of libretto for Act I, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Early version of libretto for Act II, undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Early draft of full libretto, undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Early drafts of full libretto, undated (2 items) (Box 3, Folder 39)
      (pages 1 and 2 reversed)
    - Libretto for Act I, Scene 1, undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
      (contains markings; found with first sketch of Act I, Scene 1)
    - Libretto for Act I, Scene 2, undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
      (contains markings; found with first sketch of Act I, Scene 2)
    - Libretto for Act II, undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Draft of libretto for Act III, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Libretto for Act III, undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Notes concerning libretto, 1978-1981 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Kay's outlines of opera, circa 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Early sketches for Act I, Scene 2, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - First sketch of Act I, Scene 1, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 46)
      (first page included with full sketch of Act I, Scene 1)
    - First sketch of Act I, Scene 2, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - First sketch of Act II, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - First sketch of Act III, Scene 1, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - First sketch of Act III, Scene 2, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Additional sketches, circa 1977 (Box 3, Folder 51)
      (found with first sketch of Act III, Scene 1)
    - Full sketch of Act I, Scene 1, 1979-1980 (Box 36, Folder 1)
      (includes first page of first sketch)
    - Full sketch of Act I, Scene 2, part 1, 1980-1981 (Box 36, Folder 2)
      (part 2 housed in different Box)
    - Full sketch of Act I, Scene 2, part 2, 1980-1981 (Box 40, Folder 6)
      (part 1 housed in different Box)
    - Full sketch of Act II, 1981-1982 (Box 40, Folder 7)
      (accompanies incomplete sketch of Act II piano reduction; see note on piano reduction page 169)
    - Full sketch of Act III, Scene 1, 1982 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Full sketch of Act III, Scene 2, 1982-1983 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous sketches and notes for Act III, circa 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Sketch of chorus part for Act I, Scene 1, circa 1980 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Sketch of piano reduction for Act I, Scene 1, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Sketch of piano reduction for Act I, Scene 2, 1980-1981 (Box 36, Folder 5)
      (page 141 appears on reverse of page 137)
    - Sketch of piano reduction for Act II, 1981 (Box 36, Folder 6)
      (incomplete; accompanied by full sketch of Act II: see note on piano reduction page 169)
    - Cast list/table of contents from holograph of piano reduction, 1981 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Portion of draft page for holograph of Act II piano reduction, circa 1982 (Box 3, Folder 52)
      (page 183)
    - Draft pages for holograph of Act III piano reduction, undated (Box 36, Folder 8)
      (pages 355, 372, 395, and 401)
    - Draft pages for holograph of Act III, Scene 1 full score, 1984 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Notes regarding "centers" (key areas), 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Notes regarding orchestration, 1980-1983 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Notes regarding chorus, circa 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Copies of pages from Act I full score, circa 1983 (Box 40, Folder 10)
      (contain markings and comments from editor)
    - Final page from Act II piano reduction, undated (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - First version of piano reduction for Act I, undated (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Revised piano reduction for Act I, undated (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Piano reduction for Act II, undated (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Piano reduction for Act III, undated (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Full score of Act I, Scene 1, undated (Box 74)
    - Full score of Act I, Scene 2, undated (Box 75)
    - Full score of Act II, undated (Box 76)
    - Full score of Act III, Scene 1, undated (Box 77)
    - Full score of Act III, Scene 2, undated (Box 78)
    - Notes regarding corrections to score, circa 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Lists of character parts, circa 1988 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Miscellaneous notes and sketches, circa 1979-1988 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Kay's rehearsal notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Sketches of sets with note, undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Information packet, circa 1991 (Box 3, Folder 56)
      (includes biography of Frederick Douglass, opera companion material for elementary school children, "Reflections for Older Students", and bibliographies; contains markings)
  - Pantomime, 1986
    - First sketch, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Full sketch, 1986 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Holograph, 1986 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Full score, circa 1986 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Full score, circa 1986 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Two Impromptus for Piano, 1986
    (second impromptu is revised Second Nocturne, 1973)
    - First sketch of first impromptu, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 71)
      (titled "Impromptu #2")
    - Full sketch of first impromptu, 1986 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Sketches for second impromptu, 1986 (Box 28, Folder 15)
      (revision of Second Nocturne, 1973, contains holograph of Theme, 1962)